Let’s face it – most of us can’t resist a cup of tea or coffee sometimes.
说实话，我们大多数人有时都抵不住一杯茶或一杯咖啡的诱惑。
They’re a perfect pick-me-up and comforter.
它们是绝佳的提神饮品，也是能带来慰藉的暖心之物。
But there are alternative beverages, so why have we chosen these as our go-to drinks to soothe our hectic lives?
市面上虽然有其他可供选择的饮品，但我们为什么偏偏选择它们作为缓解忙碌生活压力的首选饮品呢？
And which one is superior?
而这两者之中，哪一个又更胜一筹呢？
Let’s start with tea – it’s the second most consumed drink in the world.
我们先来说说茶——它是世界上消耗量第二大的饮品。
For many – especially the British – having a ‘cuppa’ is a daily ritual.
对很多人而言，尤其是英国人，喝杯茶是每天的固定项目。
The caffeine contained in it helps wake you up in the morning, and throughout the day we’ll make a brew to distract us from our work or to be sociable.
茶里含有的咖啡因能帮你在清晨唤醒身体，而在一整天的时间里，我们也会通过泡茶来暂时从工作中抽离，或是借此进行社交活动。
And according to some scientists, habitual tea consumption can have some health benefits.
一些科学家表示，养成喝茶的习惯对健康也有一定益处。
Andrew Steptoe, a professor from University College London’s Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, told BBC Food that drinking black tea “may speed up recovery from the daily stresses in life… but we do not know what ingredients of tea were responsible for these effects on stress recovery and relaxation”.
伦敦大学学院流行病学与公共卫生系教授安德鲁·斯特普托在接受BBC美食栏目的采访时称，喝红茶“或许能加快人们从日常生活压力中恢复的速度……但我们目前还不清楚，是茶叶中的哪些成分在调节压力恢复和身心放松方面发挥了作用”。
Coffee is tea’s ‘trendier’ rival.
咖啡则是茶的“更时髦的竞争对手”。
Its popularity has grown over the years, and this is reflected in the number of coffee shops we see around – places to hang out, do business or catch up with friends.
这些年来，咖啡的受欢迎程度持续攀升，我们身边随处可见的咖啡馆就是最好的证明——这些地方是人们消磨时间、洽谈业务或是和朋友叙旧的好去处。
Coffee can taste great and can be served in many ways, but it’s sometimes how you have it that can be seen as a status symbol or the preserve of hipsters!
咖啡的口感香醇，饮用方式也多种多样，有时喝什么类型的咖啡，甚至会被看作是一种身份象征，或是潮人们的专属喜好！
Of course, it gives you a strong caffeine hit – roughly double of that contained in tea.
当然，咖啡能带来强劲的咖啡因提神效果——其咖啡因含量大约是茶叶的两倍。
However, too much can lead to anxiety.
但饮用过多则可能引发焦虑情绪。
Sleep scientist Matt Walker told the BBC that caffeine can decrease the amount of restorative deep sleep you have.
睡眠科学家马特·沃克在接受BBC采访时表示，咖啡因会减少人体的恢复健康的深度睡眠时间。
But some scientists say drinking coffee – and green tea – can also be good for us.
不过也有科学家指出，喝咖啡——以及喝绿茶——同样对我们的身体有益。
Researchers at Osaka University linked drinking a daily cup of coffee with a lower risk of death among both stroke survivors and healthy people, while drinking seven or more cups of green tea was associated with a lower risk of death among both heart attack and stroke survivors.
大阪大学的研究人员发现，对于中风幸存者和健康人群而言，每天喝一杯咖啡可以降低死亡风险；而对于心脏病发作和中风的幸存者来说，每天饮用七杯及以上的绿茶，也可以降低死亡风险。
So, whether we turn to coffee or tea for its taste, its image or as a lifestyle choice, it could be a lifesaver!
所以，无论我们是因为口感、潮流形象，还是出于生活方式的选择而爱上咖啡或茶，它们都可能成为守护健康的“救星”！